<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-04T17:46:38-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">RocketWorld!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/personal/2019/03/25/RocketWorld!.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RocketWorld!" /><published>2019-03-25T09:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-03-25T09:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/personal/2019/03/25/RocketWorld!</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/personal/2019/03/25/RocketWorld!.html">&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, I was volunteering through the International Society for a program called RocketWorld. A group of people, each from a different country, goes to an elementary school here in the suburbs of Manchester and just introduces the students to their country - the landmarks, culture, food, etc. Of course, my country to show off was the US, so I had photos of the Statue of Liberty, Mount Rushmore, the Hollywood Sign, the White House, among other different memorials and sights. I was showing off “southern/NC things”, like BBQ and hushpuppies, showing them a map of North Carolina and photos of the Raleigh skyline and my parents’ house in Cary, in an attempt to try and share some of America that might not be as mainstream across the pond as New York City or Los Angeles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got some general questions, like “Where’s New York?” or “Where does Lebron play?” or “Do you see YouTubers around a lot?” (this last one was lost on me - I was never much of a YouTube vlog watcher). But then… it began. I showed a picture of the US Capital, which a lot of kids thought was the White House at first, and then I followed that up with a picture of the White House, and a kid at the back said “OH That’s where TRUMP lives”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background&lt;/strong&gt;: Manchester is a very diverse city, with tons of international students and then just people from everywhere in Europe and from around the world. Near to my dorm, there is an area called Curry Mile, which has at least 60-70 Indian/Afghani/Syrian/Pakistani restaurants, so there is a large amount of Hindus and Muslims in Manchester and in the surrounding suburbs. This school is representative of the population, where there are tons of brown kids and even some little girls wearing hijabs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the groups shuffled through, people kept mentioning the “orange” man and even some of the teachers asked me about his policies and how he has changed the reputation of the country and all I could really do was smile and nod. One little girl, wearing a hijab, came up to me and asked, “Does Donald Trump hate Muslims?” — In that moment, I froze. The teacher of the group turned to look at me and waited for my response.  In my mind, I was conflicted. Do I tell this girl the truth that, yes, our elected leader has attacked Muslims in the media, implemented a Muslim ban (which another student asked about later), and has insulted refugees and immigrants from any and every country (except Scandinavia, apparently), regardless of religion or race? Is it my place to tell her this, as opposed to her parents or the teacher that is currently watching me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I ended up doing was tell her that “Umm no, there has just been some people that have attacked America in the past, and he’s just very cautious about that and immigrants in general, even though that isn’t really a problem anymore.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I should have said instead and what I regret not saying, is that, “Yes, he might, but him alone. He doesn’t represent all of America. Regardless of what you hear in the news and from him, the people of America are the most welcoming and if you ever come, they’re some of the nicest people in the world and would love to have you over.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever someone asks me what race or ethnicity I am, I say Indian. I’m from North Carolina, born and raised, but I’m an Indian.
Through conversations with other first-generation immigrants (either born in US or immigrated at a very young age), I see that more and more, it’s the case that people identify as American or (insert race here)-American. Through my experiences, especially recently with the above-mentioned RocketWorld event, more and more, I’m increasingly less and less proud to be an American.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And before anyone reads into this too much - I know that I’m blessed to be from a country like America where I’ve been given so many different benefits (free K-12 education, stable government, the ability to practice my religion, etc.) over my 21 years. I’m thankful for what I’ve been given.
But in criticizing my government and asking for more, I’m utilizing one of those rights and benefits I’ve been given - to vocalize my concerns and complaints and work for our country to be better than it has been in the past few years (or increasingly we’ve seen, decades).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In America, we hear about what our government does and in a sense, we turn a blind eye / the news cycle moves too fast to have any sort of sensible reaction or action about it from the people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abroad, this isn’t the case. What small amounts of news they hear about the US is the big and the bad stuff. From the little girl above, to the other elementary school students and teachers talking about our president, to an Iranian man I met a few weeks ago saying that he hates our government but not American citizens — it really shows how much our reputation and standing in the world has taken a hit in the last few years.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A few weeks ago, I was volunteering through the International Society for a program called RocketWorld. A group of people, each from a different country, goes to an elementary school here in the suburbs of Manchester and just introduces the students to their country - the landmarks, culture, food, etc. Of course, my country to show off was the US, so I had photos of the Statue of Liberty, Mount Rushmore, the Hollywood Sign, the White House, among other different memorials and sights. I was showing off “southern/NC things”, like BBQ and hushpuppies, showing them a map of North Carolina and photos of the Raleigh skyline and my parents’ house in Cary, in an attempt to try and share some of America that might not be as mainstream across the pond as New York City or Los Angeles.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">People Watching</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/personal/2018/07/02/People-Watching.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="People Watching" /><published>2018-07-02T09:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-07-02T09:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/personal/2018/07/02/People%20Watching</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/personal/2018/07/02/People-Watching.html">&lt;p&gt;(Written August 3rd, 2017)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People-watching has a bad name; when people say they do it, it’s with a laugh that it’s rude or unbecoming of a courteous human citizen. I think it might be one of the most important things people can do in a public place and let me explain why.
(FYI when I say people-watching, I mean just watching and observing, not cracking jokes and insulting people and how they look. Inherent of people-watching is the tendency to judge, but controlling this is fairly easy in my humble opinion.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;REASON 1:
As babies, how do we learn to do our basic actions? By observing and mimicking our parents.
As kids, how do we learn what is right and wrong in public ? By watching what’s appropriate and what is not.
When we are put into a new situation, for example, a dance performance. How do we know what’s the right move? We watch the choreographer or the person next to us and observe. We imitate and improve upon their actions and make it our own.
How do we learn about our friends, loved ones? We watch how they act in situations, how they react to unexpected events, and how they handle themselves in everyday life.I’m sitting in an airport for the first time by myself. How am I supposed to act to not draw suspicion, to give off the impression that I have been here before, that I’m not a “noob”? I’ve learned from watching, from example, and I know there are certain things to do and certain things not to do so that I can not bring attention to myself and be left alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;REASON 2:
David Foster Wallace (I’m going to keep referring to his speech, “This is Water”, so just read it if you are an “avid” reader of my blog, of which there are probably 2 of you) talks about how we are hard-wired to think in the first person, to think that we are the center of the universe and to somehow (rather egoistically and self-centered) connect everything that happens in the world to us first, before worrying about anyone else.  Yeah yeah, we all say that we are not self-centered and worry about others first, but I can guarantee that when someone happens to swerve in front of you on the highway, we all start yelling expletives and wondering what the hell is wrong with that person and how they are crazy or a loser or not doing anything important with their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a public place, just look at the person sitting next to you, or across from you, or really anywhere around you. Imagine how they got there, what they’ve been through, what they’re thinking of, what their life story is. As DFW said, that guy who swerved, maybe it’s “being driven by a father whose little child is hurt or sick in the seat next to him, and he’s trying to rush to the hospital, and he’s in a much bigger, more legitimate hurry than I am - it is actually I who am in his way.” JUST maybe, that could be the case. It could be a 1 out of 1000 times case, but just maybe it could be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another benefit is that by maybe doing this, we figure out our prejudices and mistakes. Just because we might see someone in ragged clothes, looking unshaven and maybe not taking care of themselves in appearance, is it written in our DNA to automatically define them as a bum? Nope. It’s how society, maybe not as a direction, but more subliminally, has taught us to think. That person could really be having the best time of his life, happier than the rest of us could ever be, doing what he loves, and maybe just not having the time/resources to buy new clothes or whatever the case may be.  In more extreme cases (not to cause tensions or play on stereotypes), a black man in a hoodie or a brown guy with a turban or a long beard; neither of them have to be gangsters or terrorists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To watch people and to wonder what the’ve been through, to respect the path they took to get to where they were, to learn from their actions, to realize that we might be making mistakes in how we view our fellow man, and to understand that the world contains a lot more than the 5-foot circle around you, that’s what the importance of people-watching is to me.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">(Written August 3rd, 2017)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First Post!/Growing up</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/personal/2017/10/15/First-Post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Post!/Growing up" /><published>2017-10-15T09:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-10-15T09:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/personal/2017/10/15/First%20Post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/personal/2017/10/15/First-Post.html">&lt;p&gt;(Written August 7th)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I sat in the quiet train car of an NJ transit and looked at the rain-drenched towns, houses, and people through the window, I thought it would be a good time to make this first blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(To all of you that had a second to spare to come to my website and decided to read what I wrote today, thank you. For years, even maybe until last week, I thought that my words and ideas may not be worth posting on a website that maybe 10 people would go to and that would have no impact on them or on really anyone in the long run. Ehhh but what the heck, I’ll do it anyway.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a conversation with a friend one day in the middle of Washington Square Park in NYC, and does anyone want to take a guess what it might be about? Imagine, in the middle of one of the greatest cities in the world, full of vices and temptations and so many attractions, what could two 19-year-old Indian teenage boys be sitting and talking about that would warrant this post? I’ll give you a second to guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Before I continue, I want to assure you that this will not be some philosophical essay that will make you rethink your life and try to help you change your life for the better. I have no idea if what I’m doing is right or wrong, but for fun I thought I’ll write something out and just see what happens.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SO back to the story.
We were talking about how we’ve been lied to all our lives. As children, we all saw our parents act with purpose, make incredibly important life decisions, take care of us, and enjoy life all at the same time. We wanted to grow up to be like them, to know all the answers, to have the magic sauce, to live every day with purpose and intent and make the right decisions. And because of this, as humans always do, we focused not on what we have, but on what we thought would come and wished for it to come even faster. Rather than enjoying our childhood, we pleaded with the gods or whatever we believed in to make time go faster like in sitcoms and just throw us to the time where we didn’t have to deal with school, homework, studying, or our parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Funny story about that one though. NONE OF IT IS TRUE.
The magical power we all thought would come to us once we hit the age of 18 or 19 or 20 or every next number…it doesn’t exist.
We wasted our time as kids hoping to be older and “settled”, but now we’re stuck, flopping around like fish, trying to breathe in the air and adapt to the newfound power and responsibilities we have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually we’ll flop back into the water and start swimming like our parents did, making every right movement, succeeding in life. Eventually we’ll forget all about the time where we didn’t know what the hell we were doing and maybe that there was ever a time that we were above the water. (If you want a better thing to read than this blathering post, read “This is Water” by David Foster Wallace.) But while we’re here, we should take advantage of it. Revel in the ignorance and not knowing what the right decision is, how it might affect us in the future, how it could fix everything or ruin it all.
Obsessing about the future ruins things in the present. Looking to the future, not enjoying where you are, fearing of missing out on something else but not taking every potential opportunity and living life to the fullest, that’s where everyone loses. Now or later, it’ll happen.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">(Written August 7th)</summary></entry></feed>